等一下，在进屋之前 我要你知道我爱你
Wait. Before we go in,I just want you to know that I love you.
我蜜月时玩得很高兴
I had a great time on our honeymoon.
我等不及 要跟你共度一生了
I can't wait to spend our life together.
你还戴着 那条贝壳项链？
You're sticking with the shell necklace,huh?
你们回来了
You're back!
快进来
Come on in!
你们蜜月玩得开心吗？
How was the honeymoon?
我们很开心，最棒的是 我们认识了一对很棒的夫妇
So much fun. The best part is,we met this great couple.
那是最棒的吗？ 这真的是很棒的蜜月，老虎
That was the best part? Good honeymooning,tiger.
他们很酷 他们也是去度蜜月的
They're cool. It was their honeymoon too.
他们就住在城里
They live here in the city.
我们能打电话给他们吗？ 现在打会不会太快了？
Can we go call them? Is it too soon to call?
我们很兴奋 我们终于认识一对夫妇朋友了
We're excited. We finally have a couple to hang out with.
你们想要那么做吗？
Oh,were you looking for that?
对
Well,yeah.
夫妇朋友？你是说两个人吗？ 像是一、二，两个人
A couple? Like two people? Like one,two people?
那不一样 葛瑞格跟珍妮结婚了
It's different. Greg and Jenny are married.
葛瑞格跟珍妮？ “嗨，葛瑞格，我是钱德”
Greg and Jenny? "Hi,Greg. I'm Chandler."
“嗨，莫妮卡，她是珍妮” “嗨，珍妮，嗨，莫妮卡”
"Hi,Monica. This is Jenny." "Hi,Jenny. Hi,Greg."
-他们真的很棒，如果你们… -你知道吗？
-They're great. If you just.. -You know what?
快送我们纪念品 然后滚出去
Give us our souvenirs and get out of here.
-我们没有机会… -你是在开玩笑
-We didn't get a chance to.. -You're kidding!
-我们没有买任何人的礼物 -好漂亮的项链
-We didn't get anything for anyone. -Nice necklace.
你可以把它拿走
That you can have.
本集播出：录影带风波
The.One.With.The.VideoTape
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
主演：寇妮考克斯
主演：丽莎库卓
主演：麦特勒布兰
主演：马修派瑞
主演：大卫修蒙
-欢迎你们回来 -蜜月还好玩吧？
-Welcome home. -How was the honeymoon?
太棒了，你们呢？ 你们要有宝宝了
Great! How about you? You're having a baby!
没错，那真的很刺激
Yeah,we are. It's so exciting.
我就知道 你们会未婚生子
I always knew you two would have a child out of wedlock.
-你看，我有宝宝的超音波照片 -太棒了
-Look,I have a sonogram picture. -Good.
罗斯，宝宝遗传了你的黑色卷发
Ross,it's got your wavy,black lines.
现在罗斯知道了，到底是怎么发生的？在什么时候？你们做了几次？
Now that Ross knows,how'd it happen? When? How many times?
莫妮卡，那么问是不对的，从你们在哪里做开始说吧
Monica,that's not right. Start with where.
事情发生在六个星期前
It happened about six weeks ago.
我回到家，发现罗斯也在 他跟乔伊混在一起
I got home and Ross was there. He'd been hanging out with Joey.
别客气，兄弟
You're welcome,buddy.
对，谢谢
Yeah,thanks.
我有很多事要做 罗斯主动说要帮忙
I had a lot of work,and Ross offered to help.
我们边喝酒边聊天
We had wine,we got to talking.
接下来 罗斯采取主动
Next thing you know,Ross comes on to me.
那么说是不对的
That's a little misleading.
-什么？ -你刚刚说的谎话
-What is? -The lie you just told.
-我说是你主动的？ -没错
-That you came on to me? -There's the one!
-但那是真的，老实一点吧 -没错，老实一点吧
-But you did. Let's be honest. -Yes,let's.
罗斯，希望这有帮助，我不相信你
Ross. If it helps,I don't believe you.
那不重要
It's not important.
重要的是我们要生孩子了 谁先泡谁（应该用宾格）并不重要
What's important is,we're having a baby,not who came on to who.
是“谁”才对
"Whom."
没错
That's right.
-你先吻我的 -是你求我的
-You kissed me first. -You were begging for it!
你发暗号给我
You were sending me signals!
我发暗号给你？ 谁觉得是我发暗号给罗斯求他的？
I was sending signals? Anyone think that I'd send Ross begging signals?
请举手
Please,show of hands.
别人怎么想并不重要 事情真的发生了
It doesn't matter what people believe! It happened.
或许我得小心一点 我正在发送讯号吗？
Maybe I need to be more careful. Am I sending these signals now?
-你知道吗？别谈了 -告诉我我是怎么求你的
-You know what? Just drop it. -Show me how I begged you.
我可以证明 我都录在录影带里了
I can show you! I have it on videotape.
那只是一种表达方法
It's an expression.
瑞秋，快开门 听我解释
Come on,Rachel,open up. Let me explain.
-她还是不让你进去？ -对
-Still won't let you in,huh? -No.
我要把门关上 我们得好好讨论你们的事
I'm just gonna close this door so we can talk about you.
我不敢相信 他录下他们做爱的经过
I can't believe he taped them having sex.
对，你得先告诉对方 才能开始录影
Yeah. You gotta tell a girl before you tape her.
那是菜鸟才会犯的错误
Such a rookie mistake.
-你知道谁有很棒的摄影机吗？ -葛瑞格跟珍妮？
-Know who has a great camera? -Greg and Jenny?
-我要打电话给他们 -快打吧
-I want to call them. -Let's call.
问他们有没有 买纪念品送给朋友
Ask them if they brought their friends souvenirs.
喂，第八街外送餐厅
Hello. 8th Street Deli?
快挂掉，光跟他们说话 你就会食物中毒
Hang up. You get food poisoning just talking to that place.
-抱歉，打错了 -来吧，宝贝
-Sorry,wrong number. -Here you go,babe.
喂 又是外送餐厅
Hello? It's the deli again!
好吧，我要吃三明治
All right,I'll have a sandwich.
我想这个电话号码是错的
I don't think this number's right.
-什么？ -你们拿到假的电话
-What? -You got fake-numbered.
-什么？没有人会那么做 -我想我们会
-What? People don't do that. -Oh,I think we do.
-他们为什么要那么做？ -我不知道
-Why would they do that? -I don't know.
你们聊的很开心 你问了那些很棒的问题
You were a delight. You asked those great questions.
你也很风趣 老是在开玩笑，你真的很耍宝
And you were never funnier. Joke,joke,joke! You were a hoot!
你们还有我跟菲比
You still got me and Phoebe.
对不起 我不要葛瑞格跟珍妮的退货
Excuse me,I don't want Greg and Jenny's rejects.
瑞秋不肯跟我说话 她不肯开门
Rachel won't talk to me. She won't open the door.
我很好奇是为什么，变态
I wonder why,pervert.
好吧，我不是变态
Okay,I am not a pervert.
变态都是那么说的
That's,like,the pervert motto.
你举起手，把左手放进裤子里 然后再说一次
You raise your hand,put your left hand down your pants and repeat that.
我不是故意要拍瑞秋
Filming Rachel was not planned.
事情的经过是这样的 乔伊可以帮我作证
Here's what happened. Joey can back me up.
还记得一个半月前 我跑去问你一个问题吗？
A month and a half ago,remember I came to you with a problem?
我的私人问题？
The personal thing?
-什么私人问题？ -关于性的问题？
-What personal thing? -About sex?
我好几个月没有性生活了？
That I hadn't had sex in months?
我知道 你在说什么
Yeah,I knew what you were talking about.
（六个星期前）
我想谈一件 我很难启齿的事
I'd like to talk about something I'm uncomfortable talking about.
没问题
Sure.
你跟你妈 一起洗澡？
How about you showering with your mom?
我真的有问题
I actually had a topic in mind.
我正进入了 性停滞期
I'm kind of going through a dry spell,sex-wise.
-有好几个月了吗？ -五个月…
-For,like,months? -Five,to be..
骗人的，是六个月
lying. Six.
六个月？那一定很难熬
Six months? That's rough.
没有那么糟糕 我学着去欣赏一些小事，譬如说…
It's not all bad. I'm learning to appreciate the small things,like..
鸟叫声 跟天空的颜色
the sound of a bird and the color of the sky.
天空是蓝色的，罗斯 我昨天做过爱了
The sky's blue,Ross. And I had sex yesterday.
拜托帮帮我 今晚我有约会
Please help me. I have a date tonight.
我得顺利完成 我很担心我的健康
It has to go well. I'm scared for my health.
我有个点子 我想出一个故事
I got something. It's this story that I came up with.
非常浪漫 听到这个故事的女人都会心动
Very romantic. Any woman that hears it is putty.
说吧
Tell it to me.
你听完后 一定会想跟我上床
Now,you're gonna want to have sex with me when you hear it.
记住，那只是一个故事
Remember,it is just the story.
我会试着控制自己
I'll try to control myself.
多年前 我在西欧自助旅行…
Years ago,I was backpacking across Western Europe..
-你在西欧自助旅行？ -六个月后见
-You were backpacking across Europe? -Have a nice six more months.
抱歉，求求你 你去了西欧，然后…
I'm sorry. Please,please. You were in Western Europe,and..?
我在巴塞罗那郊外 在第比达包山脚下徒步旅行
I was outside Barcelona,hiking in the foothills of Mount Tibidabo.
-太棒了 -谢谢
-Nice. -Thanks.
我走到小路的尽头 发现了一座湖
I was at the end of this path,and there was a lake.
它非常隐密 四周都是高大的树木
Very secluded. There were tall trees all around.
那里非常安静 美极了
It was dead silent. Gorgeous.
我看到在湖的对面 有个美女在洗澡
And across the lake I saw a beautiful woman bathing herself.
但她在哭
But she was crying.
为什么？
Why?
酒真的很棒
This is great wine.
它是法国酒
It's from France.
法国在欧洲
In Europe.
就在西欧
Western Europe.
几年前 我在西欧自助旅行
A few years ago I was backpacking across Western Europe.
-真的吗？ -等一下，后面的故事很精彩
-Really? -Wait,it gets better.
对，我在巴塞罗那
Yeah,I was in Barcelona.
我在巴塞罗那念过一年书
I studied for a year in Barcelona.
-是吗？ -对，你什么时候去的？
-You did? -Yeah. When were you there?
-8… -89年？
-Eighty.. -Nine?
83年
Three.
那时我才13岁？
I was 13?
-总之我在徒步旅行… -我喜欢徒步旅行
-So anyway,I was hiking.. -I love hiking!
那真的太棒了
That's great!
我在第比达亚波山脚下 徒步旅行…
I was hiking along the foothills of Mount Tibidaybo..
-我想是“第比达包山”才对 -你想说这个故事吗？
-I think it's "Tibidabo." -Do you want to tell the story?
约会还顺利吗？
How'd your date go?
太棒了 我正要过街去做爱
Great. I'm across the street having sex right now.
-你的故事烂透了 -是你说的方法不对
-Your story sucks. -Then you didn't tell it right.
-告诉我你是怎么说的 -不，我不想谈
-Show me how you did it. -No,I don't want to.
-你上次看到裸女是什么时候的事？ -我在西欧…
-How long since you seen a girl naked? -I was backpacking..
-我没有感觉 -我在巴塞罗那郊外徒步旅行…
-I'm not feeling it. -I was outside Barcelona,hiking..
-罗斯，我不热，你很热吗？ -我六个月没做爱，每天都很热
-Ross,I'm not hot. Are you hot? -It's been six months. I'm always hot.
你不是在说故事 你根本就不相信它
You're not selling the story. You don't believe it.
我得走了，我有约会 但试试这招
I gotta go,I got a date. But try this.
学我在试镜前做的那一招
Do what I do before an audition.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
不
No.
我会用录影机来自拍 看看哪里做错了
Use my camera to record yourself and see what you're doing wrong.
我会试试看
I'll try that.
已经设定好了，可以拍了 按下录影键就可以了，祝你好运
Now,you're all set up. Good to go. Just hit record. Good luck.
如果你跟女人约会出了问题 我可以帮你接手
If you ever have any problem with the ladies,you know I'll help you out.
那对我来说意义重大
That means a lot to me,man.
需要我帮你效劳吗？ 要擦镜头吗？电池还有电吗？
Can I get you anything? Lens cleaner? Your battery okay?
罗斯，谢天谢地你在这里 你得帮我
Ross,thank God you're here. You have to help me.
你在自言自语吗？
Were you talking to yourself?
那会比较不丢脸 对，没错
That's less embarrassing. Yes. Yes,I was.
她一走进来 我完全忘记录影机的事
When she came in,I totally forgot about the camera.
录影机一直在拍 录下了整个经过
It kept rolling and recorded everything.
我们得看看 那卷录影带
Yeah,we're gonna need to see that tape.
那是个好主意 那会让瑞秋原谅我
What a great idea! That'll get Rachel to forgive me.
少来了，那就像是在看 探索频道…
Come on,it'll be like watching the Discovery Channel..
只不过我们知道那两只猴子是谁
only we'll know the monkeys.
听着 我不会让你们看我们的性爱录影带
Look,I'm not gonna let you guys watch us.
-我自己都没有看过 -我可以用我的两卷录影带跟你换
-I haven't even seen it yet. -I'll trade you two tapes of me having sex.
谢谢，我很感激
Thanks,I'm good.
我们不是要看性爱画面…
We don't wanna see the dirty stuff..
-我们只想知道事情是怎么发生的 -不，瑞秋会杀了我的
-just the stuff leading up to it. -No. Rachel's gonna kill me as it is.
那对她来说不公平 忘了录影带的事吧
It's not fair to her. Let's forget the tape.
谢谢
Thank you.
-不 -你说的对
-No. -You're right.
-乔伊，不 -我了解
-Joey,no. -Loud and clear.
我不明白为什么 他们要给我们假的电话号码
I don't get why they'd give us a fake number.
如果他们知道自己在做什么 他们不会给你们真名
If they knew what they were doing,they didn't give you real names.
或许有人会给假电话号码 但没有人会给假名
Maybe people give out fake numbers,but not fake names.
嗨，肯亚当斯 很高兴能认识你
Hi. Ken Adams. Nice to meet you.
瑞吉娜佛兰姬
Regina Phalange.
-我们没有做错事 -我知道
-We didn't do anything wrong. -I know.
虽然你说了 很多冷笑话
Although you did tell an awful lot of jokes.
你说它们很好笑 快说笑话吧
You said they were funny. Joke,joke,joke!
说笑话…
Joke,joke..
-是你问了太多问题害的 -我的问题怎么了？
-It was your questions. -What about them?
你问了太多问题 那像是跟谜题先生（蝙蝠侠中的角色）坐在一起
The sheer volume. It was like flying with the Riddler.
-那也是笑话吗？ -那也是问题吗？
-Was that another joke? -Was that another question?
罗斯还在吗？
Is Ross still here?
小心点，亲爱的 有人在问问题了
Watch out,honey. Someone else is asking questions now.
不，但他告诉我们发生了什么事 那真的是个误会
No,but he told us what happened. It was an honest mistake.
如果我把我跟你做爱的过程录下来 你会有什么感觉呢？
How would you like it if I had sex with you and I taped it?
算我没说
Oh,forget it.
他来了，我孩子的父亲 西部的色情片之王
There he is,the father of my child,the porn king of the West Village.
那是个意外，行吗？
It was an accident,okay?
我觉得很难过 我发誓我还没有看过它
I feel bad. I swear,I didn't even watch it.
总之，拿去吧
Anyway,here.
或许亲手毁了它 你会觉得舒服一点
You might be more comfortable destroying it yourself.
谢谢
Thank you.
什么？
What?
-你们不想看这玩意吧？ -我们当然想
-You don't want to see this,do you? -Hell,yeah!
我不会让你们看这个
I am not gonna show you this.
我们不是要看性爱镜头 只是想看你们怎么开始的
Not the sex part. Just the stuff leading up to it.
算了，让她毁掉吧
Forget it.
我们会想其他办法 解决“谁先主动”的问题
We'll think of another way to put the "who came on to who" thing to rest.
快想
Come on now,think!
那是瑞秋的录影带 她想怎么处置它是她的自由
It's Rachel's tape,and she can do whatever she wants.
她想毁了它 别说了
And she wants to destroy it,so end of story.
-我想看 -什么？
-I want to see it. -What?
你不希望我们看录影带
You don't want us to see this.
你不希望我们看它 让我想要看个究竟
You so badly don't want us to see it that it makes me want to see it.
我们到底要不要看录影带？
Are we watching the tape or not?
-我是要保护你 -我不相信你
-It's for your sake. -I don't believe you.
我想你不希望 他们看到你求我
I think you don't want them to see you begging me.
-瑞秋，拜托 -这是预告部份
-Rachel,please? -Oh,a little preview.
好吧，我要这卷录影带 证明我是想保护你
Fine. I want the record to show that I tried to take the high road.
因为再过五分钟 我会说…
Because in about five minutes,I'm gonna be saying..
好吧，要开始了
Okay,here we go.
我好快乐
I'm so happy.
谢天谢地你在这里，快帮帮我 你是在自言自语吗？
Thank God you're here. Help me. Were you talking to yourself?
-我出现了 -你就要怀孕了
-There I am. -You're gonna get pregnant.
我搞砸了
I screwed up so bad.
好几个星期前我告诉莫妮卡 我会把喜帖寄出去
I told Monica that I'd send those wedding invitations weeks ago.
你没有寄？
You didn't do it?
我把它们放在办公桌上 直到今天才想起来
I put them in my desk at work,and forgot about them until today.
亲爱的，没关系的 客人都来了，我没事的
Sweetie,it's okay. Everybody made it to the wedding. I'm fine.
-但你把我的手弄痛了 -我知道
-Kind of hurting my hand though. -I know.
我不敢相信 何况莫妮卡每天都在盯我
I can 't believe it,especially after Monica went on and on about it.
喜帖在这里，瑞秋 小心点，瑞秋
"Here are the invitations,Rachel. Be very careful,Rachel.
拜托，别在喜帖附近 喝东西，瑞秋
Please,drinking no liquids around the invitations,Rachel."
你们在我们的喜帖上面做爱？
Did you do it on our invitations?
我们没在寄出去的喜帖上做
Not on the ones we sent out.
你们在我们拿去装裱 剩下来的喜帖上面做爱？
So just the ones you gave back to us and we had framed?
感觉上像是 他们昨天才订婚
It seems like yesterday they just got engaged.
我知道
I know.
还记得他们订婚那一晚吗？ 你跟我差一点…
Remember the night they got engaged? How you and I almost..
我记得我们差一点就做了
Oh,I remember how we almost.
你觉得 我们真的会做吗？
You think we would've gone through with it?
你觉得我们会做吗？
You think we would have done it?
我知道我想做 但我不知道你要不要
I know I wanted to. I just wasn 't sure if you did.
我也想
Oh,I wanted to.
那么我们两个都想
So we both wanted to.
真有趣
Interesting.
总之这样的结果 或许是最好的
Anyway,it probably worked out for the best.
没错
Yeah,sure.
再过十秒他就要吻我了
In about 10 seconds,he kisses me.
再过五秒你们就会知道为什么
In about 5 seconds,you'll see why.
我有没有跟你说过 我到西欧自助旅行的事？
Did I ever tell you about the time I backpacked through Western Europe?
准备看她求我吧
Get ready to see some begging.
-是你对罗斯主动的 -什么？
-Oh,you came on to Ross! -What?
现在我好快乐
Now I'm so happy.
-什么？ -你用了欧洲的故事
-What? -You used the Europe story!
那是你想做爱时 会用的魔法故事
That's the magic story you use when you want to have sex!
-你怎么知道那个故事？ -你怎么知道那个故事？
-How do you know about that story? -How do you know about that story?
是一个家伙 告诉我朋友艾琳的
My friend Irene heard it from some guy.
就是我
Some guy!
不，她说那个家伙 叫做肯亚当斯
No,she told me that his name was Ken Adams.
我是肯亚当斯
Ken Adams!
大家都知道 欧洲的故事？
So,people are familiar with the Europe story?
关于“谁主动”的问题 那真的不重要
About that,the "who came on to who" thing really doesn't matter.
反正结果圆满就好了
It would have happened either way.
你说的对 我知道我很快乐
If you hadn't initiated it,I know I would have.
-那是个神奇的夜晚 -没错，它很神奇
-It was an amazing night. -It was. It was amazing.
你觉得它看起来会很神奇吗？
You think it looked amazing?
我不知道 我真的没看
I don't know. I honestly didn't watch it.
对，我也没看
Yeah,me neither.
至今为止
Yet.
-那应该会很奇怪 -对，它真的很奇怪
-That may be weird. -Yeah,it would be really weird.
-祝你好运 -祝你好运
-Good luck. -Good luck to you.
-我可以消音吗？ -麻烦你了
-Mind if I mute? -Oh,please.
-我们开始脱衣服了 -你脱衣服的速度真快
-There go the clothes. -You are undressing awfully quickly.
我六个月没做了，瑞秋，六个月
Six months,Rachel. Six months.
-我们看起来很不错 -我也那么认为
-We look pretty good. -I was gonna say.
-你的皮肤晒得很漂亮 -谢谢
-Nice tan. -Thank you.
那个周末 我刚去过海边
I'd just gone to the beach that weekend.
-你有在健身吗？ -我一直在健身
-Have you been working out? -I have been working out.
这比我之前的经验 要好得多了…
This is so much better than I ever..
那真的很难看
Oh,that's not pretty.
-快停下来 -不
-Make it stop. Make it stop. -Oh,no!
葛瑞格跟珍妮的电话号码 完全不一样
Greg and Jenny's number is totally different in here.
-我有问太多问题吗？ -没有
-I don't ask too many questions,do I? -No.
-真的吗？ -绝对没有
-Really? -Absolutely not.
-真的？ -天啊
-Really? -Oh,God.
我敢说电话号码的事是个误会 我要打电话给他们
I bet that phone thing was some sort of mix-up. I'm gonna call them.
喂，葛瑞格吗？ 我是飞机上跟你们见过面的莫妮卡
Hello,Greg? This is Monica from the plane.
听着，你给我的电话号码 853…
Listen,the number that you gave me,8-5-3..
珍妮老是给别人 他们的旧电话号码
Jenny's been giving out their old number!
那真的很像珍妮的作风
Jenny! That is so Jenny!
你们下星期六 要跟我们一起去玩吗？
How would you like to get together next Saturday?
好吧，星期天呢？
Okay,how about Sunday?
下星期呢？
Okay,the week after that?
下下星期呢？
The week after that?
你知道吗？ 我们是很会问问题的幽默大师
You know what? We are interesting,funny people with good questions.
如果你跟你的宝贝珍妮 不能了解…
And if you and your precious Jenny can't see that..
一月十五日？
January 15?
到时候见
We'll see you then!